### Emil Reji

#### **Profile**

I'm a full stack Software Engineer based in the Greater New York City Area. I am a co-founder of Stagehand Framework, a drop-in service for automatically deploying and managing review apps for front end applications. I have experience in a variety of technologies including, but not limited to the Ruby and JavaScript Ecosystems. I've worked on agile development teams and can build applications using AWS while using industry standard tooling like Git, GitHub, and Docker.

#### **Professional Experience**

#### **Co-Founder, Software Engineer,**

08/2020 - present

Stagehand-Framework 🛮

- Researched a variety of topics for Stagehand including common web app architectures, AWS resources, generic application build processes, static site generators, common client side APIs, and much more
- Designed and implemented the AWS infrastructure using a Cloudfront CDN, IAM Permissions, Cloudformation Automation, Lambda@Edge Functions, and EC2 Instances
- Used Github Actions to automate review app creation and tear down in response to Github events
- Used service workers and other client side code to implement a dashboard for the review app users while simultaneously solving our complex routing issues
- Created an npm package to provide a simple CLI that pulls together Stagehand's architecture
- Co-authored Stagehand's case study and delivered a presentation on it
- Collaborated daily with the rest of Stagehand's remote team

#### **Software Engineer, Senior Associate, Infosys**

09/2018 - 08/2020

- Worked as a tester and a developer with the following technologies: Java, Spring, Oracle, SQL, Python, Angular, Jenkins, Agile, etc.
- Was selected as part of Infosys's #FlyingHigh Associate Success Stories
- Gained extensive experience working remotely across multiple time zones world wide

#### **Education**

#### Bachelors of Science in IT, Minor in Computer Science,

2014 - 2018

Montclair State University

GPA of 3.725 on a 4.0 scale

#### Information Security Certificate,

2016 - 2017

County College of Morris

#### Skills

# **Back End**Node.js, Express, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, REST API's, GraphQL, Java

#### Front End JavaScript (ES6), React, Redux, HTML/CSS, Gatsby, Next.js, jQuery

#### **Cloud** AWS, Digital Ocean, Heroku, Vercel

## **Tooling/Other** *Git/Github, Docker, Agile, Jenkins*